

KOLTEN FLUCKIGER

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

PORTFOLIO

https://koltenfluckiger.com https://github.com/koltenfluckiger

PROFILE

Highly technical, team-oriented professional with over 3 years of extensive experience in software development. Creative, analytical and enthusiastic; a productive team player with a deep passion for technology. Demonstrated ability to work through a problem effectively and provide the best solution. Proven ability to apply concepts of objected oriented programming

CONTACT

12177 W Overland Road

Boise, Idaho 83709

208-614-.0724

koltenfluckiger@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

SYSTEM ADMIN

TAOS | MAR 2018 - PRESENT

- Created automation software with Python interacting with monitoring API
- Working with client in creating, and monitoring system infrastructure hardware/software
- Working knowledge of Nagios with Opsview Monitoring Software
- Working within an Agile development like environment to complete daily tasks

PROMOTIONAL COORDINATOR BODYBUILDING.COM | DEC 2013 - MAR 2018

- QA running promotions to prevent financial losses
- Trained in JIRA- File help desk tickets to help resolve, track, and document system issues
- Assisted with numerous projects Worked with DPG with replacing HTML code on the website

SENIOR ADVISOR

TELEPERFORMANCE | JULY 2012 - DEC 2013

- Provided feedback through coaching and developing Advisors
- Ensured understanding on company policies and expectations with Advisors
- Communicated with multiple departments through Help Desktickets

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

- Implementing core applications according to application's needs
- Experienced with making full stack applications from start to finish
- Preferred stack: MERN(MongoDB, Express, React, NodeJS)
- Experienced in deploying apps to production Koltenfluckiger.com
- Experienced in creating RESTful CRUD APIs
- Focus on developing code with SOLID principles in mind to create reusable, and testable code
- Experienced with GIT, source control to track projects, and document code changes
- Motivated to learn and implement new technologies and frameworks

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: HTML, CSS, SASS, Javascript, React, NodeJS, Express, Python

Database: MongoDB, postgresql, MySQL

Development: Object-Oriented Design, Design Patterns, SOLID, DRY, API Design, Database

Design

ADDITIONAL CAPABILITIES

- Ability to communicate effectively both in writing and verbally
- Self-motivated for continued learning and coaching opportunities
- Experience working in a team environment
- Self-Starter and self-learner for developing new skills and using new technologies
- Comfortable working directly with clients to build software fit to their needs

EDUCATION

Mountain View High School | Aug. 2007- May 2011

Meridian, Idaho

• Major: Information Technology